import { Exercise } from ".";

export const ANIMALS: Exercise[] = [
  {
    "question": "кошка",
    "answer": "koszka",
    "extra": "🐱"
  },
  {
    "question": "собака",
    "answer": "sobaka",
    "extra": "🐶"
  },
  {
    "question": "птица",
    "answer": "ptica",
    "extra": "🐦"
  },
  {
    "question": "рыба",
    "answer": "ryba",
    "extra": "🐟"
  },
  {
    "question": "лошадь",
    "answer": "łoszad´",
    "extra": "🐴"
  },
  {
    "question": "корова",
    "answer": "korowa",
    "extra": "🐄"
  },
  {
    "question": "кролик",
    "answer": "krolik",
    "extra": "🐇"
  },
  {
    "question": "овца",
    "answer": "owca",
    "extra": "🐑"
  },
  {
    "question": "свинья",
    "answer": "swin´ja",
    "extra": "🐖"
  },
  {
    "question": "волк",
    "answer": "wołk",
    "extra": "🐺"
  },
  {
    "question": "тигр",
    "answer": "tigr",
    "extra": "🐅"
  },
  {
    "question": "лев",
    "answer": "lew",
    "extra": "🦁"
  },
  {
    "question": "слон",
    "answer": "słon",
    "extra": "🐘"
  },
  {
    "question": "мышь",
    "answer": "mysz",
    "extra": "🐭"
  },
  {
    "question": "медведь",
    "answer": "miedwied´",
    "extra": "🐻"
  },
  {
    "question": "обезьяна",
    "answer": "obiez´jana",
    "extra": "🐒"
  },
  {
    "question": "утка",
    "answer": "utka",
    "extra": "🦆"
  },
  {
    "question": "курица",
    "answer": "kurica",
    "extra": "🐔"
  },
  {
    "question": "пингвин",
    "answer": "pingwin",
    "extra": "🐧"
  },
  {
    "question": "лягушка",
    "answer": "l´aguszka",
    "extra": "🐸"
  },
  {
    "question": "змея",
    "answer": "zmieja",
    "extra": "🐍"
  },
  {
    "question": "коала",
    "answer": "koala",
    "extra": "🐨"
  },
  {
    "question": "верблюд",
    "answer": "wierblud",
    "extra": "🐪"
  },
  {
    "question": "панда",
    "answer": "panda",
    "extra": "🐼"
  },
  {
    "question": "лиса",
    "answer": "lisa",
    "extra": "🦊"
  },
  {
    "question": "еж",
    "answer": "jeż",
    "extra": "🦔"
  },
  {
    "question": "орел",
    "answer": "oriel",
    "extra": "🦅"
  },
  {
    "question": "попугай",
    "answer": "popugaj",
    "extra": "🦜"
  },
  {
    "question": "дельфин",
    "answer": "diel´fin",
    "extra": "🐬"
  },
  {
    "question": "акула",
    "answer": "akula",
    "extra": "🦈"
  },
  {
    "question": "осьминог",
    "answer": "os´minog",
    "extra": "🐙"
  },
  {
    "question": "краб",
    "answer": "krab",
    "extra": "🦀"
  },
  {
    "question": "черепаха",
    "answer": "czieriepacha",
    "extra": "🐢"
  }
];
